Look at this
Just step in
Will cause 1 million people to delay receiving goods
please be careful
But we want everyone to see
We are bad
Come
Let's take everyone inside
actually
Smart warehousing
it has a
Very big features
A way to make money you’ve never thought about
It's here
Hi guys
I'm here to introduce you to your strange industrial knowledge.
super serious boy
You know in everyone's home
Everyone has a need to store things.
That is, the warehouse
Taiwan is a technological island
There are people broadcasting live every now and then.
Some people are shopping online
Someone is betting on S price
So there are many people who want to rent a warehouse
Then come and stock up some goods
So then a very strange business emerged
When you have an empty basement
Empty tin factory
Still an empty space
Someone will tell you
Otherwise, I will turn it into a warehouse and rent it to others.
What about this so-called warehouse?
It's actually a tin house
It can be used to make money
Then there are some wealthy companies
Or there are some small and medium-sized companies or large companies
they will want to say
Our company is so big
Otherwise we will build a place
this place
Just call it a warehouse
But the most interesting part is
Like some science park
Or maybe it’s an industrial company with a big brand name?
Its warehouses are worse than those in Thailand
Worse than some places in Southeast Asia
Not even a warehouse management system can do it
Anyway, just leave everything there.
Then wait for one day
it will burn
why many people
Knowledge about this industrial warehousing
Very weak
Because actually forty or fifty years ago
Our manufacturing industry in Taiwan
It's too powerful
What about industrial land?
It basically serves two purposes
One is to build a factory
One is for warehousing
So there is a lot of industrial land
Everyone uses it to legally register the company.
Then what
Build an illegal small warehouse nearby
Or is it?
Going to places that are clearly not industrial areas?
Go rent some illegal warehouses to use
Then come and stock up
I believe that friends who watch our channel
That is, many people have the need for warehousing.
Or are you at work today?
You also want to rent a small warehouse
Then sell some small things
Start a small business
In fact, the warehouse is basically
You can see several aspects in the regulations
one
Safety
What about the material of the cover inside it?
Is it constructed with fire-resistant materials?
Not when it's burning
Suddenly out of control
Then the second kind
What is Taiwan afraid of most?
earthquake
What about when the earthquake collapses?
Will the goods inside you be crushed?
Or will the goods inside be produced?
The second, more serious harm
Then you have to look at its structure
Look at its steel structure
Or look inside its RC building
Does it comply with relevant government regulations?
Usually after considering the first two considerations,
Think about the third one again
Its location and transportation
Does it meet your specifications?
Because why are you renting a warehouse?
Save money
Make money
So if your warehouse is in a deep mountain forest today
Just the cost of driving to deliver goods
That's very high
Then you won't make any money at all
All spent on logistics
Then at the same time you want to say
Are there any traffic controls?
A bigger business
Needs like we want heavy vehicles to enter
Does it have any special restrictions?
You have to think about this too
There is another
Are there any strange factories built nearby?
Or a chemical plant that burns easily
do you know
We once photographed a place
Then it was next door to it
Just blow up the whole thing
I know
do you know
You went there, right?
And the week it burned
In fact, we just happened to be surveying there.
It's a very large factory in the south
Then something unexpected happens
We almost...
burned
The third thing you need to pay attention to is
When you buy and sell today
There are some things that are fast fashion
There is something food
There will be some shelf life
When you are looking at the lease contract for the warehouse
The more flexible the better
That’s why I won’t jump over the wall like a Buddha during the Chinese New Year.
Everyone only eats it during the Chinese New Year, right?
Otherwise, who would be in May, June, July and August?
Eat Buddha and jump over the wall over there
No
So it will be particularly concentrated at that time
So what happens after that?
derived from a
It is public comprehensive management
I won't say it
I only have those one or two months out of the four seasons in the year
Buying and selling before Chinese New Year
It will be useless after the Chinese New Year
So at this time, some people started to want to say
Otherwise, all of us will rent one together
but what will be
dispute
As long as someone
There will be disputes
So in fact, there are many, many types of warehouses
As a person who has been running around outside for a long time,
people running around
Warehouse I've seen
From the strangest warehouse type
Tin house type
I saw super high-tech ones along the way.
And there are even unmanned warehouses with absolutely no people inside.
What do you want?
Click twice with your mobile phone
It will be sent directly to you
So when you hear this
You will find that running a warehouse is actually a business
But back to the basics of industrial knowledge
In fact, the planning of the warehouse is a very wise one
Something learned
How do you make the same space
Same floor effect
How to keep costs to a minimum
And at the same time, you can earn money from customers
What do you need for this?
Dr.Super
Industrial knowledge
The last two items are the ones that are most easily overlooked.
Is your warehouse insured?
So is it legal and compliant?
So today we as industrial knowledge
What I’m showing you is definitely not this kind of iron-clad warehouse.
Let’s take you to see a technology called smart warehousing
When doing business, we have to go high-end
Today I will lead you
How to start a small business by yourself
Be a little boss
Also there is no need to move your room
your toilet
your mother's balcony
your mother's dressing table
All are used to stockpile goods
So how do we start ordering goods and doing business?
First you need a truck
And then take your truck
Drive to the pier
Stand-in
this is too close
I'm afraid I'll crash someone's dock
What's next?
Place your goods at the inbound workstation
After putting it away
It's none of your business
What about after the goods are shipped?
He will measure its size
its weight
And then there's its height
What about after all these things are passed?
Our AGV will pick up our goods
Look at this
Just step in
Will cause 1 million people to delay receiving goods
please be careful
But we want everyone to see
We are bad
Come
Let's take everyone inside
Anyway, it’s just 1 million people
Taiwan 23 million people
(loves to joke)
Everyone, wait a moment and the goods will be S, right?
So suppose
If we are goods
can i stand on it
Of course not
Because I just didn't take any measurements
I came through the aisle next to it
If I want to stand on it and become a commodity
Then I was just about to pass through that gate.
So after
Let’s take a look at the AGV after it comes in
Have you seen this below?
small details
These are the channels of AGV
Then what
The AGV next to you will carry your different goods
pull out
What kind of goods do you want to bring in?
Inside this warehouse
How high and deep is this warehouse?
Just the height
Just forty meters high
And what about its depth?
One hundred and ten meters deep
What is its total floor area?
There are 40,000 square meters
There are more than 80,000 in total
AS/RS pallet storage (automated warehousing system)
With over 170 piers
And you see, the pier now looks like this
But you know its exterior design
It's a rotating lane
Why do everyone in logistics hate waiting for the freight elevator?
And then the advantage of them using the rotating lane is
Each of your trucks
You can drive directly to the floor you want.
No need to wait for the freight elevator
It can also save money on electricity bills
And what about this one you see now?
It is currently the largest in Taiwan
Smart Warehousing Omega 2 Bayberry
And it was
It is the first in Asia
Now it is the second in Asia
Then do you know where the number one in Asia is now?
in malaysia
Then it's theirs too
If you are a friend studying architecture
Have you noticed the architecture of this place?
a bit special
Look at it on every shelf
It actually goes to the ceiling
Because you think Taiwan is a
Is it a place where earthquakes often happen?
So what?
you will want to say
What kind of structure
It allows the goods inside to be placed on top
Your goods are at the same time
It can help this structure
add weight
Then what
What about when an earthquake really shakes things up?
Your house and its contents
Neither will be separated
Still able to maintain a good...
"strength"
"Strength" is not quite right
have a real noun
"Structural Mechanics"
No no
Not that superficial
I remember there was one
There was once a noun
When I was reading a book on architecture
ever learned
Okay, if you major in architecture
Please tell us below
The point is
the structure of its cargo
Same as what you saw before
traditional warehouse
Actually it's different
Then you must want to say
Products from your company
Just put it in your company's warehouse properly.
Why do you want to sell goods with everyone?
Put them together
actually
Smart warehousing
it has a
Very big features
A way to make money you’ve never thought about
It's here
Friends who watch our channel
We all sell peripheral products
You know our whole company
ever shipped
Let’s build an assembly line together
highest record
do you know how much
Tight 600 orders
At that time, 600 orders
All our colleagues
producer
The concept of everyone coming together to package the goods
But what?
Smart warehousing like this
There are tens of thousands of orders a day
It can be disposed of immediately in one day
And it can be instant
Delivered to North, Central and South at the same time
Do you know if they sell towels?
to that towel
What else do you want to pick up?
What else should I pick up?
Then we put it together
You know what if I sent it to the wrong person in the end?
return
Online order checking
Go crazy
And then what about the second one?
In fact, it is with
The AI ​​era is very close now
It is to integrate the warehouse management system
Look at these two
this walkway
It is actually a purchase
One is shipped
it can be used quickly inside
to figure out what cargo dimensions
What kind of goods are you talking about?
it should be put together
This is awesome
Like we used to train a colleague
Then become our e-commerce company
Train for a year
It’s hard to get started
What's the result?
Resigned
You have to change to another person again
You need to retrain your colleagues
Manage the warehouse again
Re-manage your logistics
Is it a crash?
So actually this third one
is a boss
What I want to think about most
In fact, at least you will encounter
Just save costs
You think about it
inside your company
When you put a lot of goods
When placed in your company
The first one is your floor efficiency
The second is whether you want to ask colleagues to take care of it
Ask your colleagues to take care of it
Does he want to divide the goods?
Does he sometimes hide in the cargo?
What are you doing there?
have no idea
and then again
You want such a big warehouse?
When millions of goods are here
There will be some cute little ones
I want to smoke inside
Just want to hide
want to do something
What about the end?
fire
After burning, who do you think smokes?
no one admits
But look here
no one
Do you know what would happen if there was no one?
No one smokes
and no one
No one knows how to fight yet
If suddenly today
You suddenly feel that this thing
a bit dangerous
you want it to stop
Check and take a look
Seems no problem
OK you go
Walk...
you see
No emotional issues at all
So there is a saying in ancient times
I've said it before
Many trees must have dead branches
Where there are many people, there must be loveliness
When you are in the entire warehouse
As long as no one
Then there would be no such thing as a cutie
There won't be anyone inside who wants to light a fire and smoke.
No one would want to do anything in there.
have no idea
Do you know if today
When you become a commodity
You are in this warehouse
What kind of life are you living?
Everyone
I took everyone to the second floor
We are on the second floor now
Do you know how it is different from the first floor?
no difference
more goods
Larger warehousing
We are now on the second floor
we have to talk a little bit
That's high-end
It’s just how some rich people make money
You know like Yonglian Logistics develops them
There is a very powerful system inside
called digital transportation
If you use mechanical principles to talk about structure,
Just like a
Horizontal Opposer Engine Trading Concept
We used to buy PS5
When we went to this store to buy
People just talk about it
This is out of stock
He just said it didn't matter
Just wait for me
I'll help you arrange the goods
You wait over there for thirty minutes
After waiting for twenty minutes
We can just bring the goods over.
Why do you need to adjust the goods like this?
have you ever thought about
It’s not because there’s no stock
He wants to make this money
After a product comes from Sony,
In fact, a lot went through in the middle
agent
dealer
branch
then all the way down
Met the store manager
Which store manager, which employee
This employee’s performance bonus
So layer it all the way down
In order to meet this condition, you
So he had to go around in a big circle
Then go and arrange goods with others
Originally from this platform
To transfer to another platform
Thirty minutes is already too fast
For some goods, you have to wait three months.
But it's different here
Suppose you are on the e-commerce platform today and want to buy something
You know what's on every item
Aren’t they all in stock?
But if I were the boss today
You are the boss too
It was discovered above that I was out of stock.
Otherwise, let’s get twenty PS5s.
I can be in this warehouse
I don’t need to send it out
I trade internally in the warehouse
Your goods become my goods
But we don’t need twenty PS5s
Move it from your warehouse to my place
After transportation
Package
Distribution
Employees get goods
Tally
Ship it to you and put it in the warehouse
repackage
Then give it to the guests
I'll be in this warehouse directly
How much does your goods cost?
I'll buy it from you inside
After buying it, the money will be given to you.
Our goods transaction was successful
Your goods become mine
They're all on this shelf
Do you understand
How much money have you saved through this logic?
You didn't understand, right?
No wonder you are an employee
Choking
Having said that
You know when we watch this video
It’s almost Chinese New Year
Please at this time
What do you want to send during the Chinese New Year?
did you receive it
Dear bosses who watch our videos
The goods you want to send out during the Chinese New Year
Have you sent it yet?
Don't you know
How is your shipment going now?
I think you're finished
Just wait for the Chinese New Year
People call you to complain
So at this time
Let me tell you about the modern warehousing system
It’s different from the era we used to have
if you want to know
Today is your Chinese New Year. Is your Buddha Jumping over the Wall finished?
What to do at this time
Do you want to call your cadres over?
Ask your employees
How is our shipment going now?
but
We don't have to
You just take out your phone
Open this APP
ALPS
Just use your mobile phone
When squatting on the toilet at home
You can know your Buddha jumps over the wall
How many have been shipped so far?
How much have you purchased for Buddha Jumping Over the Wall?
How much is left of your order now?
You haven't done much
You can do everything from this APP
You can watch it directly on your mobile phone
Then there is another one
I think this era
Things that are already gradually being phased out
Have you ever helped others transport goods?
Or someone who has shipped or purchased goods
You all have this impression
It was when we delivered goods in the past
Everyone needs that stuff
Like this and then pile it next to it
then
I delivered it to him
Then he was next to
Get the goods
Why did you do such cute things before?
It's because sometimes when delivery
Yes, I will obviously leave the goods to you.
You can pick it up with me that day
No, I have no impression. I forgot.
Right? I can’t fully explain it.
So at this time you can also
take out your phone
Open this APP
you can see
The photos he recorded for you when he delivered the goods
Just make sure this product is OK
The box was not smashed
Number of pieces of goods
Also in the photo
Counting is that the quantity is correct
And the point is
You know when you ask around over there
That credit is gone
We used to be manufacturers that worked together through thick and thin.
suddenly overnight
The relationship is wrong
Pigs and sheep change color
I won’t be able to continue my business in the future.
Why bother
So I just said
As long as no one
there won't be
conflict
So this time comes
Friends who want to change jobs after the Chinese New Year
It doesn’t matter if you don’t understand logistics
Can you do IT?
Where did the program for this mobile app come from?
from here
Situation room
Situation Room, everyone.
all goods
With the data on your phone
It’s from within this system
It escaped and entered your mobile phone
past before
People build warehouses or rent warehouses
It is actually completely separate
But now
They can help you build it
Rent for you
Help you use it
If you can't find someone, he can help you find him.
You don’t know where to put your goods and warehouse
You can also find this company
Come and plan for you
Maybe now you see this kind of video
you will want to say
That person who used to take care of the warehouse
Wouldn't there be no job?
Just the people we used to move goods here
Isn’t there nothing to do?
But you have to know
According to the data of the entire environment
In fact, less than 50 years later
Taiwan's population
He has less than 15 million people left
So actually everyone
We should all go and take the time
Spend it in more meaningful places
So if you keep insisting
Conservative at a very strange sticking point
If you don't want to change
then you will
It’s not a happy life anyway
Anyway, 50 years later
Our channel will no longer be there
Just go back and think about it
-What I told you 50 years ago
And you know this type of company
The advantage is
If you are very interested in software
Or what about this kind of logistics arrangement?
Or...
Do you like playing with Lego?
I think if you like playing with Lego
You are a very logical person
In fact, they are all suitable for doing
This kind of company work
But you know watch from my side
You see these simple reports
With simple goods in and out
Do you know what I saw?
You don’t understand, right?
Let me ask you
If the volume of my goods is too large
Our financial report for the entire market
Before it even appeared
I can already sit in this situation room
Then he looked at it and said
The sales of this company's products have been huge recently.
This thing behind it
I know which company made it
In fact, all in all
you know
many business practices
Talk to a lot of business-minded people
It is discovered from many small things
You see a long time ago
In fact, no one has thought about it
It turns out that the warehouse can do this
a long time ago
Everyone wants to do their own thing
I never thought about it...
all people
Then put the goods together
Then everyone distributes the goods together
Let’s reduce the intermediate costs
Then let a professional team
to manage your goods
Good luck everyone
I tell you
opportunity to make money
from now on
You know now
Everyone likes to live in buildings, right?
Think about the inside of your home
Are there too many?
Inside the strange cabinet
I'm piling up some inexplicable and unnecessary things.
your child's toys
your wife's clothes
The only things that come out every year during the general cleaning
Put it back after cleaning
The next time we meet will be next year.
Is there such a thing?
So you look at the system we see today
It’s a very large system
But have you ever thought about what would happen if you were inside the building in the future?
There is a community warehouse in the building
Are there any children's toys?
We become the same thing
Throw it into the community warehouse
Just inside the community warehouse
like today
and then focus it to
Inside the community’s smart warehouse
Today I want to play with Lego
Click on a number
Don't press randomly
Then this product will
Delivered to your doorstep
after playing
Then throw it back into the community’s smart warehouse
Dear construction companies
I told you a way to make money
community management committee
You can earn warehouse operation and management fees
And your community won’t be there just because there’s no one
No one pays management fees
When there are fewer people in your community
It means the bigger your storage space is
You can make money from outsiders' warehousing
Give you a way to make money
I hope you can find one after the New Year
better job
or a lifestyle you prefer
What I mentioned above is actually just one part of the logistics industry.
A small part of warehousing
Did you know that the logistics industry is actually a very powerful job?
It's like talking about a war happening today
If you want to send ammunition to the front line
When you want to let it continue to fight against others
Then you need to use logistics at this time
And earlier
When you don't have internet
Not when buying things online
In fact, the standard bureau is also a kind of logistics.
Just give things to others
Just give me what you think is important
That is a kind of logistics behavior
So do you know what kind of person is suitable to work in the logistics industry?
Is there a logistics department?
There is no logistics department in Taiwan, nor are they bodyguards.
And it’s a logistics industry
like this company
The largest number of them are actually in the Department of Civil Engineering
And the Department of Urban Planning
There is also the Department of Information Security
Do you know why information security professionals work in the logistics industry?
Why
Never thought about it
Let me tell you, there is a place
Do you want to attack Taiwan every three days?
Does he really want Taiwan to be chaotic?
That's what I said
All he needs to do is hack into Taiwan's logistics system
Keep toilet paper from being delivered to convenience stores
Prevent toilet paper from being delivered to your home
You don't use toilet paper for three days
Do you think Taiwan will be in chaos?
You don’t have to wipe your feet for three days
Let you eat for three days without toilet paper
Let me see if you go crazy
So in fact, the logistics industry
is one that few people see
But something extremely important
There’s a lot more to talk about in it
So if you like we're talking in depth
For more logistics content
You can click like below
Then when we know
We can take photos of more detailed logistics content later.
The above is the boy with hyperphonia
See you next time
Goodbye
Wow, staff restaurant
Colleagues here can eat for free.
Then I should be considered a colleague today
Curry rice, three-cup chicken, braised beef brisket
Fried pork ribs
Beat and throw pigs
What do you think is delicious?
Braised Beef Brisket Rice
Now the logistics era has changed. You see?
Dining room
Look at his table
Do you know what this table is?
In the past, people from logistics companies and production lines
Everyone likes to squat on the production line and eat
The purpose of this design
Just to make them feel like they are still eating on the production line
And its chair is
Navy chairs have different approaches but the same purpose
The navy chair is a very classic design
And the whole thing is made of aluminum
The purpose at that time was to let people on the sea
If someone is really unhappy and fighting with each other
This chair cannot be broken or broken.
So they designed a navy chair
The whole thing is made of metal
their company
stainless steel
And it’s padded butt won’t freeze
One with both attack and comfort
chair